# KHADIJA MISFER Y ALJURAIB

Eastern Province, Dhahran ♦ khadijajuraib@gmail.com ♦ linkedin.com/in/khadija-a-37a809202 ♦ 966-50-632-2299

## Software Engineer | Programmer | Product Developer | Technical Solutions Specialist

A strategic and highly technical Software Engineer with 4 years of professional experience creating, designing, and implementing technical solutions and software products. Possess a wide range of knowledge in applications and programming languages, offering superb analytical and computer skills to help organizations grow client bases. Possesses a passion for computer science, curiosity and enthusiasm for new technology, and the ability to quickly learn new ideas by continuously exploring ways to expand technical expertise and education.

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Coding, Scripting, Debugging Data Privacy & Cyber Security Data Structure UML & Algorithms

E-portfolios & Report Writing Data Analytics & Research PHP Software Engineering Approaches

Cross-Functional Teamwork Client Relationship Management Project Planning & Implementation Web Design & Database Management Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) Team Communication & Collaboration

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Third Place Gold Certificate ◆ Misk Academy **Best Entrepreneurship Laides ◆** *Intrapreneurship, Youth Saudi Ladies*  2021

#### 2021

## **PROJECTS**

## CyberHAT Invention for the Misk program (Third Place Gold Certificate)

December 2021

Designed, created, and implemented an IoT-based smart hat for improving safety and productivity at construction sites, launching a one-of-a-kind, real-time field reporting system through integrated sensors. Served as the best SaaS solution, along with supporting software and mobile apps for keeping track of workers' safety and productivity.

## **Employee Reimbursement Application**

July 2021

Automated the reimbursement process from manual to digital for universities/institutes/companies that allows employees with certain benefits like insurance, gym, family meals, academic and leisure tours, etc.

Scanning Component April 2019

Developed and implemented a scanning component for PMU ID by using SQL Server.

#### Course Record-Keeping Application

April 2019

Created a database project in MySQL that kept track of all completed courses.

Plants Watering System May 2018

Designed and developed an automatic electronic system to feed the plants when dry using a water sensor and arduino.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Clinical Administrator, ACCEL International Saudi Inc. ◆ Eastern Province, Dhahran

November 2022-Present

- Manage the therapist team, oversee staff schedules, communicate with physicians and higher management, and administrate facility finances and regulatory compliance.
- Perform projects to work on quality improvement, ensuring the efficiency of the facility and the quality of services.
- Process billings and patient fees and monitor the facility's budget and spending. Create finance reports regularly.
- Train staff members, audit performance, and manage the medical supplies maintenance or records management.

## Software Engineer / Programmer, Google ◆ Eastern Province, Dhahran

January 2020-November 2022

- Supported the organization's goals by aligning technical processes, development strategies, decision-making, and maintaining team communication.
- Oversaw various projects' entire software development lifecycle, from requirement gathering, analysis, data modeling, design, architecture, development, testing, documentation, and deployment.

- Developed simple to complex plans and roadmaps within the scope of assigned projects and evolved roadmaps to meet established client requirements, technical specifications, and infrastructure needs.
- Designed and vetted systems structures and wrote product development codes to solve ambiguous problems.
- Reviewed codes developed by other engineers, performed UATs and provided feedback to ensure the program's compliance, accuracy, testability, and efficiency.

## Software Engineer, Fiverr & Upwork ◆ Freelance

May 2019-November 2022

- Developed projects for databases, frontends (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP), and Java programming for different clients, serving as a partner and trusted contractor and delivering scalable and insightful solutions.
- Created websites, applications, and databases, wrote programming codes, and performed UAT for client systems.
- Implemented technical solutions to client's issues by optimizing resources and enabling more efficient processes.

### **CERTIFICATION & TRAINING**

Software Testing Cisco • Cisco
Software Architecture Cisco • Cisco
Google Career Certificates • Google
Electronic Developing Course

July 2021 June 2021 April 2021

September 2020

## **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering ♦** *Prince Mohammed Bin Fahd University* 

August 2021

#### SKILLS

**Applications:** C, C++, C#, Java, Matlab, SQL, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, JavaScript, Mobile Applications

Languages: English, Arabic

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

Scholarship from Ministry of Higher Education (2014-2019) Public Speaker (2019-2021) Computer Engineering Department ACM (2014-2015) Scholar President

President